15. Class and Accent. The words and ideas you express are important, of course, but
nearly as important is the way you sound when you express them. Indeed, there are still
people in the world who will judge your accent before they even consider your words. You
may even have your own biases. There are a few distinct accents in the United States.
People from the South are said to draw, speaking slowly and stretching their vowels out. Some
people find this accent reassuring. Others think it sounds unintelligent. One accent from
Southern California with very rounded vowels has been mocked in TV and movies as the dumbest
accent in America. New York and Boston accents can sound decisive or rude, depending on the
manner. In England, accents have always been very important. Even these days, children
with undesirable accents are sent to elocution lessons where they are taught how to speak
like the upper classes. Many studies show how people respond to accents. Scottish accents
are seen as reassuring. People with accents from the Midlands of England are seen as untrustworthy
and may suffer career discrimination as a result. People from Liverpool are thought
to sound unpleasant, while people from Ireland apparently sound sexy. In many countries,
people with city accents may be seen as smarter, wealthier, and more accomplished than people
who clearly sound like they are from the countryside. Your accent, of course, reveals nothing but
where you grew up—not your intelligence, not your trustworthiness, and not your value.
Being able to use different accents and different situations may help people avoid prejudice,
but it would be better for all of us to recognize our own irrational biases and fight against
them.